JOSHUA EBRANI

Software Engineer

(516) 423-1130 JoshuaEbrani@gmail.com Greater NYC Area **PORTFOLIO GITHUB** LINKEDIN

SKILLS JavaScript, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, React, Redux, SQL, SQLite3, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, Git, Webpack, JQuery, Mongoose, MongoDB, Express, Node, AWS

PROJECTS

MASHBOOK (Ruby on Rails, React, Redux, PostgreSQL, CSS3, HTML5, Webpack, Heroku, AWS) Social media platform where users can create accounts with personal profiles, create posts, and comment on other users' posts.

live | github

- Guaranteed the safety of user privacy through frontend and backend user authentication utilizing BCrypt to hash and salt
- information on the backend, and custom react-router components to limit certain functionality until signed in.
- Used Redux to provide context of universal frontend state to components at various levels of app hierarchy efficiently.
- Incorporated react pattern of ternary logic to ensure only a post creator could edit or delete his/her own posts/comments.

DEFEND MY FOOD (JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Canvas, Webpack)

live | github

Purely frontend tower defense game.

- Constructed a game grid system by drawing an individual cell box on each iteration throughout the canvas, while also having the ability to place defenders in the desired cells through mouse click functionality.
- Implemented a collision detection algorithm used for projectiles and attackers/defenders, determining a collision through calculations of the x and y coordinates and height and width of the objects.
- Developed a modulo-based function for randomized projectile creation, shooting a new projectile on each iteration.

PETFLOW (React, Redux, MongoDB, Express, Node.js, Heroku, CSS, HTML)

live | github

PetFLow tracks the expenses spent on pets to help users optimize their spending while also giving their pets the care they need.

- Worked with a team of software engineers in implementing the MERN stack as a backend API for the application.
- Administered CSS to create a clean website experience that is easily readable and usable to any person, of all ages.

EXPERIENCE

Financial Analyst

Uber Capital Group Aug 2019 - Dec 2020

- Evaluated the financial feasibility of commercial real estate loans through complex underwriting and deal level risk analysis; including analysis of property level income statements, rent rolls, leases, and borrower financial information.
- Built out the company's custom underwriting models, resulting in a 40% speed up in the underwriting process for investment properties in the industries: Multifamily, Construction, Retail, Industrial, SFR Portfolio's, and STNL's.
- Coordinated with the Capital Markets division to arrange debt financing from institutions such as: Life Companies, CMBS intermediaries, and Commercial Banks.

Director

Learn It Up

Sept 2018 - Present

- Spearhead a community program where 150+ young adults join together weekly to learn various areas of Jewish philosophy.
- Increased attendance by more than 100% in 2019 by coordinating various marketing strategies with our social media team.
- Lead weekly board meetings of 20 young adults to keep the program running at peak efficiency.
- Delegate responsibilities among the board members in a professional manner.

EDUCATION

App Academy - Rigorous 1000-hour software development course with <3% acceptance rate | Winter 2021 **CUNY Queens College** BA - Dual major in Corporate Finance & Economics | 2016 - 2019

Relevant coursework includes: Statistics, Calculus